Hey everyone, and thanks for dropping
back into the cryptoverse.
Today, we're going to talk about
Bitcoin, the beauty of mathematics, part
72.
If you guys like the content, make sure
you subscribe to the channel, give the
video a thumbs up, and make sure to
check out the upcoming ITC conference in
Miami, November 20th through the 22nd.
Link will be in the description below.
Before we move on, I'm actually speaking
at a conference before the ITC
conference.
It's actually in
of all places, New Zealand. So, I'm
actually I'm I'm speaking at the
Canterbury Tech Summit in Christchurch,
New Zealand. This will be taking place
September 16th of 2026.
So, I look forward to seeing you guys
there. I was actually looking at my
channel analytics. This shows So, over
the lifetime of the channel, I started
it in June of 2019,
uh you can see that if I scroll all the
way down,
you can see that 1,599
of you that are subscribed to the
channel are in fact are in fact from New
Zealand. So, almost 1,600 people that
subscribe here are from New Zealand. I
will be there in about a month and a
half. So, I hope to see you I hope to
see some of you guys there. I'll leave a
link to this conference down in the
description below. Uh if anyone wants to
wants to take a look at it. All right,
so it's the
Tech Summit
uh 2026.
Um so, check it out.
All right, let's go ahead and jump in.
So,
the asset class is still coming in well
below the quote-unquote fair value
logarithmic regression trend line. We
have said
throughout this year that this is likely
going to continue, and it could get
worse because the fair value
is a monotonically increasing function
that continues to go up. So, even if we
were just to go sideways, it would
become more
uh undervalued relative to that value to
the fair value. But, the point is is
this is still very similar to what we
saw last business cycle. It's just that
the four-year cycle top happened to
align with the post-apathetic top
digestion phase,
which is unfortunate, but
when you think about it, it all it's all
been playing out very similar to 2019.
And, you know, my guess is that nothing
really changes this year.
We've talked before about how
because 2026, the bear market arrived
right after the apathetic top that
corresponded to the four-year cycle top,
that we were likely going to may remain
very undervalued for the rest of the
year. And, and even in line with the
four-year cycle, it would suggest that
things could actually get worse
uh before they get better. So, you know,
I'm not opposed to this thing going even
lower. Um
still in line with the four-year cycle.
If you take the percent difference
between uh the that fair value
regression trend line and where we are
right now, you can see that it is is is
pretty low. Right? I mean, we have been
lower before all the way back when
crypto first launched. Actually, it was
the only time that it's been lower uh
than it is right now. I mean, it kind of
makes sense. You know, I mean, we've had
a long time,
17 years basically, since Bitcoin's been
around, since 2009.
And, there's been a lot of dubious
speculation. There's been a lot of
promises. But, the reality is is, you
know, crypto has a problem. And, the
problem is that so much of it is is
scams, meme coin rug pulls, presidential
rug pulls,
which is kind of crazy. But, then
it is what it is. Um but, then recently
you have the, you know, the
the hacks um
in some of these cold storage devices
that I'm sure people have seen and you
know, I it's tough because you know, one
one company there's a security
vulnerability and then a lot of people
lose their Bitcoin. And it's sad to see.
I would encourage people to you know, to
go make sure that their Bitcoin is
secure and whatnot. But the asset class
is going through some growing pains.
That's what's happening right now. It's
going through some growing pains and it
could become even more undervalued.
Remember the market does not have to
make sense at all to you or to me.
But in terms of the four-year cycle, we
are still likely to remain weak
for at least a few more months would be
my guess.
And so
if you did lose money in those in those
hacks,
you know, I I I truly feel for you. I
feel like a lot of people did what they
thought was the right thing and then
they still ended up losing. And it's
really tough to see and I think it kind
of like confirms why we continue to see
retail interest dwindle. You know, like
looking at at like if you look at
YouTube views to various crypto YouTube
channels, it just continues to drop. And
so the asset class has a problem and you
know, one of the ways that this
problem's going to be fixed is for the
asset class to again rebuke the scams
and to focus on building real things
rather than focus on ETFs and and
strategic Bitcoin reserves and all that
stuff and the Clarity Act. I mean, I
know people are still focused on that.
But I would say focus on actually making
the fundamentals better.
That would be a better focus than than
just
than just focusing on how do we get more
people in the asset class. Because what
we've seen is that a lot of people come,
but then And just leave because they
lose their money
doing something that they don't even
know is wrong. And then by the time they
realize it is wrong, money's gone and
they've lost interest. I've seen some
pretty bad takes uh by by actually some
people with a lot of followers. And what
they say is that a lot of these altcoin
rug pulls are actually good for Bitcoin
because it brings people into the space
at least. I think they are so far off
base and they're so blinded by their own
greed. And they're blinded by, you know,
their their views on the market. And so
they think that that's a good thing. But
listen, when when someone is onboarded
to the asset class and they immediately
lose all their money in a rug pull, that
doesn't make them want to put more money
in. That doesn't make them want to do
research into Bitcoin and figure out
like, you know, is it different than the
other stuff? They doesn't They don't
care about that stuff. They only care
about the fact that they came into the
market, they lost their money, and now
they're gone. They're not going to go
figure out, you know, which one of the
of the 20 million might actually be
legitimate. So,
I hope as the asset class continues to
sort of push forward through time here
that uh the industry as an as a as a
whole rewards those that truly want to
do the right thing and and you know, be
a straight shooter rather than those
that continue to just shill scam after
scam after scam. And I think we're
actually there now. I mean, I think it
is happening, but it's just taking a
long time to get here. And now that
we're here, I think it just has to go on
for a long time. And then that will be
sort of the the the maturation process
that we just have to go through as an
industry. You could argue that every
industry goes through it. And and you
could just simply argue that we are in
that phase right now. And the reason I
think we're in that phase right now is
when again, when you look at where we
are relative to the fair value, we are
as low the last time we were this low
was all the way back in 2010 and 10 when
the asset class was, you know, born
essentially. 2009 is when it was born if
you go all the way back, but 2009 2010
and it just shows you, you know, there's
been a lot of speculation,
but
we got to actually
keep people. We can't bring them to the
asset class,
have them be exposed to the worst of
things, and expect them to stay. That's
not going to happen. There's also a lot
of security vulnerabilities that the
asset class is going to have to work
through.
So, there's a lot of stuff, and you
know, again, growing pain after growing
pain. At the end of the day, the
four-year cycle still continues to work
out. I'm going to still defer to that
for now. I would look for the asset
class to probably go even more
undervalued before the year is over in
line with the four-year cycle, and
hopefully we can come out of that into
into a fresh bull market. But, those are
my thoughts. Again, I eventually think
the asset class will hit 10 trillion,
plus or minus a few trillion, and as we
go to sleep at night, we cannot help but
wonder, what's a few trillion dollars
among friends?